<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>White Paper Reading on zhengxin</title><link>https://zhengxin.online/tags/white-paper-reading/</link><description>Recent content in White Paper Reading on zhengxin</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© zhengxin</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://zhengxin.online/tags/white-paper-reading/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>[White Paper Reading] Conveyor: Continuous Deployment at Meta</title><link>https://zhengxin.online/posts/wp_conveyor/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://zhengxin.online/posts/wp_conveyor/</guid><description>Meta has released a paper titled Conveyor: One-Tool-Fits-All Continuous Software Deployment at Meta, which offers an in-depth look at the company&amp;rsquo;s state-of-the-art continuous deployment system, Conveyor. This system is integral to Meta&amp;rsquo;s operations, deploying containers over an immense scale across millions of machines.
From the paper, three key insights emerge:
Meta emphasizes the practice of continuous deployment without manual intervention. The ingrained philosophy within the organization is to &amp;ldquo;release early, release often,&amp;rdquo; with the aim of rapidly implementing bug fixes or security updates.</description></item><item><title>[White Paper Reading] Twine, cluster management system at Meta</title><link>https://zhengxin.online/posts/wp_twine/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://zhengxin.online/posts/wp_twine/</guid><description>Twine is the cluster management system at Meta, published at Twine: A Unified Cluster Management System for Shared Infrastructure.
Twine is a regional, managing the infrastructure of data centers consisting of millions of machines. It is designed to be power efficient and general for various types of workloads. To achieve this, there are 3 key design decisions they madej.
Dynamic machine partitioning. Instead of statically partitioning machines into different clusters and assign jobs to clusters, Twine design machines as dynamic resources, and can be added or removed from a logical unit called an entitlement.</description></item></channel></rss>