<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on zhengxin</title><link>https://zhengxin.online/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on zhengxin</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© zhengxin</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://zhengxin.online/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>[Paper Reading] Conveyor: Continuous Deployment at Meta</title><link>https://zhengxin.online/posts/wp_conveyor/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://zhengxin.online/posts/wp_conveyor/</guid><description>Meta has released a paper titled Conveyor: One-Tool-Fits-All Continuous Software Deployment at Meta, which offers an in-depth look at the company&amp;rsquo;s state-of-the-art continuous deployment system, Conveyor. This system is integral to Meta&amp;rsquo;s operations, deploying containers over an immense scale across millions of machines.
From the paper, three key insights emerge:
Meta emphasizes the practice of continuous deployment without manual intervention. The ingrained philosophy within the organization is to &amp;ldquo;release early, release often,&amp;rdquo; with the aim of rapidly implementing bug fixes or security updates.</description></item><item><title>[White Paper Reading] Twine, cluster management system at Meta</title><link>https://zhengxin.online/posts/wp_twine/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://zhengxin.online/posts/wp_twine/</guid><description>Twine is the cluster management system at Meta, published at Twine: A Unified Cluster Management System for Shared Infrastructure.
Twine is a regional, managing the infrastructure of data centers consisting of millions of machines. It is designed to be power efficient and general for various types of workloads. To achieve this, there are 3 key design decisions they madej.
Dynamic machine partitioning. Instead of statically partitioning machines into different clusters and assign jobs to clusters, Twine design machines as dynamic resources, and can be added or removed from a logical unit called an entitlement.</description></item><item><title>Kube-proxy and CNI plugin: What's the difference?</title><link>https://zhengxin.online/posts/kubeproxy/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://zhengxin.online/posts/kubeproxy/</guid><description>Understanding the components of a Kubernetes cluster is generally straightforward, as their names tend to hint at their functions, like scheduler. Nevertheless, the presence of kube-proxy alongside the CNI plugin within Kubernetes&amp;rsquo; networking architecture initially left me confused. My questions are:
What are the differences between kube-proxy and the CNI plugin? Are they optional in a Kubernetes cluster? To address these inquiries, it&amp;rsquo;s important to delve into the of Kubernetes&amp;rsquo; networking model and how kube-proxy works.</description></item><item><title>Explore Kubernetes Design inspired by Borg</title><link>https://zhengxin.online/posts/borg/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://zhengxin.online/posts/borg/</guid><description>Google released a detailed paper on Borg in 2015, titled Large-scale cluster management at Google with Borg. Borg plays a vital role in managing clusters in Google, overseeing numerous machines, efficiently distributing workloads among them, and ensuring optimal resource allocation.
The architectural design of Borg, as shown in the image below directly from the paper, bears a notable resemblance to Kubernetes. This similarity is expected, given Kubernetes drew inspiration from Borg&amp;rsquo;s architecture.</description></item><item><title>Iptables explore, implement virtual IP</title><link>https://zhengxin.online/posts/iptables/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://zhengxin.online/posts/iptables/</guid><description>What is netfilter In 1999, the Linux kernel was augmented with netfilter, a robust framework designed to empower users with the capability to tailor network packet processing within kernel space. Netfilter introduces five pivotal hooks distributed at key stages of the network packet&amp;rsquo;s journey, providing functionality ranging from packet filtering to network address translation. The hooks are as follows:
PREROUTING INPUT FORWARD OUTPUT POSTROUTING Packets arriving at the host are processed through the PREROUTING -&amp;gt; INPUT sequence, while packets originating from the host follow the OUTPUT -&amp;gt; POSTROUTING path.</description></item><item><title>Kubernetes networking: network namespace, veth pair and bridge</title><link>https://zhengxin.online/posts/kubernetes_networking_1/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://zhengxin.online/posts/kubernetes_networking_1/</guid><description>Kubernetes guarantees that each pod in the cluster has a unique IP address, and they can can communicate with each other using this IP address directly. You may wonder how this is achieved. We will have a series of posts that will explain how networking works in Kubernetes. And this is the first post in the series, which will explain three fundamental concepts: network namespace, veth, and bridge, that are the building blocks of Kubernetes (and container) networking.</description></item></channel></rss>